Deekshitha Juvvadi

Phone: 469-863-9313 | Email: deekshithajuvvadi25@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/deekshitha-juvvadi | GitHub: https://github.com/deekshithaj

Personal Website: https://deekshithajuvvadi.netlify.app

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX Master of Science, Computer Science

Vasavi College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India Sep 2014-May 2018 Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology GPA: 3.71

GPA: 3.49

Aug 2022-May 2024

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Deekshitha has an experience of over 4 years in web development, working exclusively on web applications in JavaScript specifically, RESTful APIs, MVC frameworks such as Spring, Springboot, Grails, integrations with Oracle SQL and developer testing in JUnit, Spock, Jasmine frameworks. During her professional work, she was the primary resource to a suite of applications and has also extensively managed and monitored the application logs and health throughout their workflows through Splunk and always focused on optimizing the performance of the web applications through data retrieval using Apache SOLR search, facilitating RESTful APIs for interaction with dependent systems, resolving support tickets and issues faced by users of Qualcomm's applications in Production, Jenkins CI/CD pipelines using Docker containerization, Kubernetes deployments. Deekshitha then started to pursue her Master's in Computer Science at The University of Texas at Dallas taking courses in Design Analysis and Algorithms, Database management, Web Technologies, Machine Learning, Big Data Management and Analytics, Information Retrieval.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript (Backbone JS, Angular JS, Handlebars JS, React JS, Node JS), HTML5, CSS3

Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, Python, Groovy

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB

DevOps & Cloud: Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS

Technologies & Frameworks: Spring, Springboot, Grails, Apache Solr, Kafka, Agile, Jira, Spock, JUnit, Sonar, Jasmine

Data Analysis & Big Data: Apache Hadoop, Apache Spark, Splunk

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Qualcomm

Apr 2021-Aug 2022

- Resolved application issues, bugs and support tickets in Production, customer queries, created dashboards in Splunk, and debugged and refactored application code optimizing the performance by 20%.
- Prototyped solution to streamline support requests raised by users by auto-resolving issues using Chatbot, saving the team approximately one hour per day.
- Developed application features, discrepancy reports, and quartz jobs which helped in developer analysis and increased the efficiency of the application by 30%.
- Contributed to building CI/CD integrations using Jenkins pipelines and Kubernetes for three applications.

Associate Programmer Analyst, Qualcomm

Jul 2018-Apr 2021

- Designed a feature to automate interaction between Qualcomm and suppliers saving 180 hours of user time per month.
- Integrated third-party software plugin Jacoco for code coverage and updated the analysis to Sonar, worked on unit testing using Spock framework, JUnit and Jasmine framework for JavaScript improving the overall application test coverage by 40%.
- The primary resource to eight applications aimed at providing resources to Qualcomm Suppliers, interacted with cross-functional teams to better the functional design of applications. Created RESTful APIs to retrieve information from dependent systems, optimizing application performance by 10%.
- Indexed data from application database into Apache SOLR and facilitated retrieval from SOLR API which enabled faster fetching of results, increasing the performance by 70%.

Intern, Qualcomm

Jan 2018-Jun 2018

Implemented a prototype for an Al-based smart assistant backed by Facial Recognition which provides daily updates, and audio feedback on body vitals such as heart rate, temperature, analyses of sleep cycles, and stress levels with an accuracy of 76%.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Quizzotic (Java AWT, Swing)

Implemented a Java application which provides a platform to conduct exams online, validate answers, calculate scores, and display grades. Operated as a hosting platform for a quiz show with over 100 participants.

Theme Box Shopping Store (React JS, NodeJS, MongoDB)

• Collaborated on building a web application similar to an E-commerce website that empowers customers to curate customized gift boxes, choose from various themes, specify quantities, add items, proceed to checkout, and complete orders ensuring a hassle-free shopping experience for users.

Search Engine (Apache Solr, Machine Learning Algorithms, JavaScript)

• Developed a search engine which gives all the information about Dogs. Crawled about 100K URLs and indexed the data into Apache Solr. Used clustering techniques such as K-Means and Agglomerative clustering methods to display more relevant results.

Weather Data Analysis and Forecast using Neural Networks(Python, LSTM)

• Constructed Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) models and implemented Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) and Multi-Layer LSTM models for comparative analysis using PySpark to manage the complexities of Big Data, for the Jena Climate dataset.

Spark Streaming with Reddit and Kafka(Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch, Kibana)

• Built a spark streaming application that will continuously read text data from a real time data source(Reddit), analyze the text for named entities, and send their counts to Apache Kafka. A pipeline created using Elasticsearch and Kibana reads the data from Kafka and analyzes it visually.

CERTIFICATIONS

- PEGA Certified System Architect (CSA) 7.2
- Coursera courses for Angular JS

EXTRACURRICULARS

Student Assistant, Eugene McDermott Library, UTD

Feb 2023-May 2024

• Worked with the library management system on issuing books to students, booking study rooms, printing services, interacted with staff, professors, students in managing the decorum of the library.

Volunteer, ACM UTD Oct 2022-Nov 2022

• Participated in Figma workshop entailing on use of Figma and its importance in requirement gathering and design specific interactions between planners and developers.

App Development Intern, The Yiddish Arts and Academics Association of North America (YAAANA)

Aug 2024-Presen

• Learning mobile development in Android Studio and currently working on integrating features such as profile management, notifications, password management features.

ACHIEVEMENTS

• Won QualStar award in the month of June 2019 for performance in developing automated feature for Engineering Wafer Buy product planners to create and manage build requests.